hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski on this podcast we talk
about ways for you to grow in your
coaching business your mentoring
business how to make more money and
increase your income now today I want to
talk about the mindset for making money
here's the thing is that in this economy
right now if you look at what uh
economists have said you have to be
making about
$150,000 to $200,000 a year to even
qualify for low middle class and
that's every like sounds insane to most
people because it hasn't been that case
for their entire life not even 3 years
ago and what's happened is that that's
that's a that's a
hyperinflationary uh cycle that has
happened in the world um it's by Design
and I think quite frankly that we are
inundated with messaging to keep us
broke to keep us struggling to keep us
from wanting to make more money because
here's the thing is people don't want to
make more money because they don't want
to pay more in taxes
uh but you got to make more to even
survive and so then if you make less you
get free resources the government takes
care of you and what this is doing is
literally creating a society and a
culture where it's better to stay broke
for most people because they don't want
to work hard enough they don't want to
gain new skills they don't want to do
the things to progress forward and by
the way if what I just said offends you
you're like well you don't know to my
situation you don't know that I I want
you to understand I'm not blaming you
what I'm saying is this is that it is 10
times harder now than it ever was but
you're going to have to either pick your
hard you're either going to be be
completely controlled pay for by the
federal government or your friends and
family or you can provide for yourself
and have a have a business or you can
work a again work a job but the problem
is most jobs are not paying you six
figures right now and so the only option
for most people is to have a business
that's what I help people with is to
take their knowledge and information and
actually create a online course digital
product business or coaching business
and I've been doing that for the last 21
years is helping people to be able to
accomplish that and so what what I want
to tell you is this is that we have to
in order to kind of reach that level we
have to shift our mindset and thinking
about
money and you have to shift out of this
like well I wish stuff was
cheaper and oh I I need to save more
mindset and oh I just need to cut back
and live like smaller because again
that's great that keeps you out of debt
that's a great first step right but you
got to shift into I got to make more
money and I need to figure out what it
takes to do that and I got to structure
my life in a way to where I can increase
my
income and you can't listen to the the
messages that are being inundated in our
society that it's evil or wrong to do
that and you're a bad person who's
taking away from somebody else for doing
that and that's just simply not
true and so if if you are listening to
this right now you know my family has
made tens of millions of dollars with
courses and coaching over the years
provided an exceptional life for my
family where I you know I grew up on
welfare I grew up in a family where we
didn't have enough money at all and by
the grace to God my mom she actually
started a business online over 31 years
ago she's one of the first people on the
internet that started a business she
didn't know what had a have a clue what
she was doing I but like by accident
pretty much made a ton of money and then
learned quite a bit over the years she's
like if I knew what I knew now back
then we might be billionaires I'm like
probably you know but like you didn't
you know 31 years ago but like she was
there at the opportunity and she she got
a couple things right but like you know
didn't barely know what she was doing
but we were at the right place at the
right time learning the internet and
then I learned a lot about how to do a
lot of stuff on the internet and just
growing up in that household got working
in the industry online sales and
marketing uh 21 years ago and have loved
it haven't looked back ever since I I
love storytelling I love telling stories
I love the way that story can shape
people but
you got to learn to sell and you got to
learn to actually get people to buy from
you and so we can't just sit around and
tell stories all day
and not pay the
bills and so that's what I had to learn
is I had to figure out okay it's not my
natural personality to sell when I
wanted to start my own business um for
the first time I I bombed completely and
said I'll never do business again I'll
just work for somebody
else this was years ago and after that I
realized there were skills that people
who make the most amount of money have
and they think differently about money
but they also think differently about
getting it and so that's what I want to
share with you here today number one
getting out of that scarcity mindset
stop listening to all of the messaging
of culture and society and everybody
else who's out there who's telling you
you need to do this in order to be a
quote unquote good person you're evil if
you're not like that's some crazy stuff
that's going out there like you're
literally being demonized for wanting to
provide for your family now
legitimately um and so you can't listen
to
that that crud that's out there and you
got to you got to shift out of a
scarcity mindset and this is going to be
one of this is probably one of the
hardest parts because we're like well if
I don't have a lot how am I not going to
be in scarcity because that's all we
know as people we're programmed to
if I don't have right now I'm in
scarcity and so we it literally tweaks
our brain to to to to not operate in
struggle even though we're in a
situation that is considered struggle
does that make
sense I'll let me explain it another way
you do not have to feel or operate as a
human based on your environment or
circumstances and that's the key and
that's the number one key that you have
to do to be able to increase your income
is you have to operate out of a
different frame and framework of your
Humanity in order to increase your
income in order to make more money
otherwise you're just going to keep
repeating the same cycle because what it
happens is you go from becoming a
certain person by believing that you are
and then your actions follow a lot of
people have it wrong where they think oh
I'm going to do something I'm going to
take action and that's going to turn me
into the person that can do these things
and that's simply not the case it always
starts internally first it always starts
up here first where you get a vision for
what you're creating you get a vision
for the life that you're creating you
get a vision for the kind of income that
you're creating you get a vision for the
kind of result that you're creating I'll
tell you this you got to maintain that
Vision because life will try to beat it
out of you right now these little
devices right here there is messaging if
you scroll your social media that is
trying to tell you to not make money and
you'll get ads that are like hey buy
this do this all that by the way I run
ads I teach people how to run ads I have
a coaching program that I run ads to to
get people to join coaching programs
where I show them how to make more money
okay so understand that I'm in that
world doing that but you cannot be a
consumer of the content that is telling
you that it's wrong to make Mone
money and you need to start paying
attention to and listening to different
voices if the internal dialogue in your
head is struggle lack insecurity doubt
fear about money what are you paying
attention to you know last week I had a
moment of a lapse of judgment shall we
say where I went on of social media and
it was right around when the stock
market had crashed they were talking
about the war with Iran and Israel and I
got scared for like a whole night I felt
some real
fear and I was operating from a place of
Terror and
fear which is
exactly the the way to pretty much like
destroy our lives is if we operate in
that and so here's what you got to do is
you got to have okay here's the
situation over
here but then
over
here these are weird props I know but
over here here's the situation of what's
going on you got War rumors of War stock
market
inflation you got to increase your
income the dollar doesn't go as far as
it did and then you have this is your
mindset where you're operating as if
those things are not the reality that
you're operating from that you operate
from abundance that I believe that great
things happen when I take action that
I'm believing that my income will be
increasing by doing these things and I
actually go out there and actually do
the work I'm not just believing but I'm
actually putting it into practice you
know one of the biggest ways to know if
you're operating in fear is if you are
not taking action on the things that you
have decided to do you're sitting around
taking a year for your funnel you're
sitting around taking months and months
and months to feel ready to put your
offer out there that means that you're
operating in fear and worry you might
not call it fear and worry you might
call it wisdom you might call it a
spirit of Excellence gosh I see people
they literally justify Their Fear as a
spirit of Excellence well I couldn't
here's how that works well I couldn't
present myself in such a
way that would make me look that way to
people without it being at a higher
level so I'm going to wait until I feel
good about it and that's wisdom no it's
not it's fear it's operating on of fear
it's operating on of worry and I meet so
many people I want to make sure I set
the perfect first
impression okay I don't mean to be cocky
here but I'm saying that that's exactly
what that
is and so when we become so concerned
with how we look to everybody
else it destroys our life I get caught
up in that trap myself as
well I've been caught up in that
trap worried about the negativity that I
hear from
people it sometimes eats away in my mind
when I can if I ruminate on it and I
have to literally stop those thoughts in
their
tracks I have to be intentional to stop
those thoughts in their tracks and to
not follow through with
them when you can learn that you have
control over your your
feelings you have control over your
perceptions you have control over over
your reality have you ever have you ever
heard like we don't have control over
our feelings we're going to just feel it
any certain way that's actually not
entirely true and and
and and again if you've experienced
trauma and all of that it is very hard
I've spent years in therapy till I
finally realized okay I actually can
control these feelings if I'm feeling
sad maybe it might take me might take me
a couple hours to not feel sad but I can
change my focus of what I'm focusing on
what am I letting be in my
imagination What am I letting operate in
my mind what am I letting control and
dominate my mental
space to start to see life in a
different perspective in a better
perspective in a clearer perspective in
one that's not worried or
fearful about what's going to
happen am I doing everything perfectly
is this all going well am I am I making
a mistake here or there am I am I doing
all the right
things we can get so caught up in our
head we can get so caught up thinking
about all the ways things can go
wrong and it's a skill to not do
that and you might say well that has
nothing to do with making money it it
absolutely does because if your brain is
is literally wired in a way to not do
the things that will make you
money because you are sitting around
waiting until it feels better for you
instead of realizing that you have
complete control over how things feel in
your
life you will be sitting around waiting
for hours and hours and hours and I
found myself doing that because I bought
into that lie for a while and I tried to
operate in
that you know what's interesting is I
never operated in that for the longest
time until I
started feeling like oh well you got to
honor everybody's you know experiences
everybody's feeling these different it's
like I'm just like okay I get that but
if you want to be in the top 1% or 2% of
people yes that's exactly where I want
to be it's exactly where I want you to
be that's exactly where my family is
we're in the top 1% of of families in
the whole country as far as income
goes
is to not
allow your feelings to dominate your
actions and to really start to become
intentional with those
things day by day by day to say I'm
going to take every thought
captive I'm going to take whatever I'm
feeling right now and I'm not going to
let that control
me and decide for me how going to be I'm
going to choose this day what I'm going
to focus
on and so if you're focus on lack you're
focused on insecurity you're focused on
your physical body is not feeling well
you're focused on all the stuff that's
not going right you're focused on your
bank account your taxes all that
stuff that will dominate your space in
the negativity now you got to still deal
with those things but you want to come
from a place of hope abundance Joy
faith
belief and what ends up happening is you
are believing for something that's
better and you end up literally guiding
your
brain controlling where you're putting
focus and then those things start to
come in your life you start
recognizing opportunities you start
recognizing what the Right Moves to make
are you start
recognizing the better choices to
make I'm going to give you a great
example right here you just heard me my
nose I have a little bit of a head cold
right now yet I making what probably one
of the best podcasts I've ever done why
because I didn't let this control me
today yes I've been taking a little bit
easier lot a lot easier I'm working at
like 50%
capacity but I knew that I had to get
this message out and I and it was it was
Friday it's when I record these podcasts
usually you know I was working on the
weekend Saturday and Sunday now I'm not
decided to make those be family time by
the way that's actually made things
really great for me mentally and our
family it's amazing and
so all that to say like no matter what
situation you're going
through we can think about all the
quotes about money and stuff like that
but where are you putting your focus
that has more to do with your ability to
increase your income than anything
else are you seeing opportunities are
you believing for opportunities are you
believing that things can get better for
you are you believing that from one day
to the
next things don't have to
suck or do you think that
well if all these things come into
alignment for me then they'll be better
are you waiting for things in your
external life to come into alignment
before you feel
good or are you
deciding what
dictates what feeling good means or
not do you know that you can actually
and this and again I have worked with
people
with any number of situations and I and
I have so much empathy for the situation
that people are
in it's a choice no matter what
situation we're in to let those things
dominate our mind
space it's a choice to let a diagnosis
space it's a choice to let
a
situation take over our
life simply because things aren't going
how we want them to simply
because the economy is going one way or
somebody's getting elected or something
I don't know who's going to get elected
in our
country you know but I know whoever is
that's not going to be what's going to
determine my
future there's there's one candidate
that's probably going to be a lot better
for business than
another but that's not going to
determine my future because I'm still
going to go to work and I'm still going
to have to decide there still going be
tough days hard
days and that's where you got a shift is
that you and your life is not determined
and dictated by what's going on in your
environment your environment will always
have things going on this week we
had well some fire ants that started
coming into our house we had to take
care of them we do natural Pest Control
natural Pest Control means we don't lay
out poison poison
with our dogs and my son he he you know
he he he chews on his
shoe right I mean he's he a little kid
like well would try not to have chew on
his shoe he chews on the velcro it's not
that bad but like you know and the dogs
they they they lay in that and they lick
their paws like and so like you got to
be careful with that so we use all
natural stuff and it's a little
different it's a little bit more
work but we took care of it
we took care of those things you know in
our physical bodies I've been on a
health Journey over the
last eight month uh almost a year really
actually it takes making decisions it
takes making
choices even when things don't feel
perfect even when we're not sure how
things are going to go to decide to do
the best thing for us now when it comes
to you actually shifting your mindset
about
money
realize that it's a blessing to ask
people to buy stuff from you for them
that you're benefiting another
person and that it doesn't detract or
take away from them that you're not
putting a burden on somebody
else for charging money for something
and then realize that that's an exchange
of
value and so then when you're able to
exchange that value with people it is a
blessing you become a blessing to others
by providing an
opportunity that you can exchange value
for and if you don't provide that
opportunity if you don't put that out
there or you're like oh I'll just put it
away for give it away for free can I
tell you this giving stuff away for free
I've tried it does not not help
people it doesn't you'll be like well
you're doing a free
podcast my business that I charge money
for helps far more people than this free
stuff that I do this free stuff is part
of my marketing material that markets to
build up my coaching
business that I use to Market to build
up the following and the audience that I
have so people know what it's like to
work with me I'm a straight
shooter not the not everybody's cup of
tea it's
okay but those that I meant to work with
they love it and their lives are changed
their lives are made better and I and
and listen every piece of content I put
out there is going to change and
transform somebody's life if they let it
but I'll tell you the ones who actually
invest get the most out of it and the
ones who invest the most amount of money
you know I have some one-on-one clients
I have some Consulting clients they've
invest tens of thousands of dollars to
work with
me and those are the ones that actually
get the
most out of working with me and so it
takes shifting
yourself out of a scarcity mindset
realizing that by charging what you're
worth you are a blessing to other
people and that you're able to be a
blessing by doing that
and that it does not have to be a
struggle it does not have to be
striving it's a struggle when we choose
for it to be again I don't mean to say
that to sound
insensitive sorry if that's offend
somebody because I know everybody's got
situations we all got issues we all got
stuff going on in our
life but we can choose
to feel amazing no matter what's going
on in our life we can choose to focus on
the the way things are working out for
us instead of against
us we can choose to see things coming
together for us in our favor instead of
against
us and that becomes a choice and that's
one of the number one choices that
people can make when it comes to making
money is
realizing that even the fact that you're
listening to this right now every moment
in your life has led up to this moment
in time right here where you're hearing
this and maybe this might be the first
time it sinks
in and then you got a choice to make am
I going to just go back to the life that
I had before and continue struggling
continuing making excuses continuing to
decide why I'm not moving forward or to
shift perspectives and to say you know
what
no matter what's going on I'm going to
decide to do something
better I'm going to
decide that my
life is not just what's been handed to
me that I'm not just going to accept
things for how they've been given to me
that I'm going to start to believe for
more believe for better start learning
the skills that I need start putting the
skills into practice start being the
person that I need to be to move forward
start showing up with a different
energy start having more faith in
possibilities start having more faith in
God and watch him and you partner
together to bring stuff together in your
life we don't have to struggle my
friends you don't have to struggle
struggle is a choice it's a mindset it
is not a
situation because you can be in any
situation and still decide that it's not
a
struggle you one of my favorite books
the meditations of Marcus
aelius talks about
this we can choose that when obstacles
come that when hard things come that
when hard situations come that we're
going to keep in happiness because
that's the only thing that's going to
help us move forward and make a better
situation sitting in lack sitting in
worry sitting in complaining sitting in
God this sucks allowing depression to
take over laying on the couch and
ruminating on how things should be
different zoning out on a social media
we end up programming our brain to zone
out instead of making our life better
and it's a
choice what are you going to choose to
do are you choose to just accept things
for how they are
again you want to accept things you want
to let go of trying to control
situations of
course it's
twofold we have to do something
different we have to set an intention
and then when we set Our intention we
let go of trying to control the
outcome we let go of that and we release
it and surrender it give it to
God and we trust that that process is
going to work we start trusting the
process we start trusting in those
actions instead of needing to control
every aspect before we we let go and put
it out there and I think that's one of
the biggest the biggest downfalls and
detriment that I meet with so many
coaches and mentors is why they're not
making that kind of money is they're
trying to control everything in their
life to make things better for
them they're trying
to force everything to come together
better for
them when what if you just accepted that
you're in the best possible situation
you could possibly be in right now no
matter what situation you're in it is
the best possible situation the best
possible
right now for you because what are the
lessons to learn in it what can you come
out of in that what can you discover in
that and when you start to see that you
start to recognize all of the
opportunities that you have everything
you need in your life right now to
accomplish and experience every dream
that you ever
had you can all right listen I hope that
this has encouraged you inspired you
share this podcast episode with
somebody listen to it again and again
and again let it sink
in and start to listen to this message
deeper G your life everybody we'll talk
soon have a good one
[Music]